http://www.cyclops-electronics.com/privacystatement/

Component Search
LoginHomeServicesNWUPC Framework AgreementElectronic Components Stocking DistributorStocked ComponentsHard to Find ComponentsObsolete ComponentsActive ComponentsPassive ComponentsShortage ComponentsDay to DayMilitary & NATO SpecificationFast Component SearchExcess Inventory ManagementExcess StockSelling OptionsPrice Match Plus PromiseScheduled Ordering5 Reasons to Use Scheduling ServiceThe Benefits of Scheduled OrderingDownloadsLine CardQuality & Testing1 Year Quality Guarantee8 Step Guide to Buying Electronic
Components With ConfidenceComponent AnalysisRoHSConflict MineralsDivisionsGlobal Supply ServicesCyclops ExcessAbout UsWhy Choose UsWhat Our Customers SayThe TeamAccount ManagersLuke WilsonRyan LawtonRyan JohnsonJordan PriceLloyd ToddSenior Account ManagersCraig BloomfieldLee HadleyJon JamesMatt PannettDean SimpsonAndy WallerInternational Account ManagersDomenico Del PapaNewsOperations MessageSign Up PageBlogExhibitions25th Anniversary| Global Electronic Component DistributorContact UsCyclops LocationContact the Team Directly
HomeServicesNWUPC Framework AgreementElectronic Components Stocking DistributorStocked ComponentsHard to Find ComponentsObsolete ComponentsActive ComponentsPassive ComponentsShortage ComponentsDay to DayMilitary & NATO SpecificationFast Component SearchExcess Inventory ManagementExcess StockSelling OptionsPrice Match Plus PromiseScheduled Ordering5 Reasons to Use Scheduling ServiceThe Benefits of Scheduled OrderingDownloadsLine CardQuality & Testing1 Year Quality Guarantee8 Step Guide to Buying Electronic
Components With ConfidenceComponent AnalysisRoHSConflict MineralsDivisionsGlobal Supply ServicesCyclops ExcessAbout UsWhy Choose UsWhat Our Customers SayThe TeamAccount ManagersLuke WilsonRyan LawtonRyan JohnsonJordan PriceLloyd ToddSenior Account ManagersCraig BloomfieldLee HadleyJon JamesMatt PannettDean SimpsonAndy WallerInternational Account ManagersDomenico Del PapaNewsOperations MessageSign Up PageBlogExhibitions25th Anniversary| Global Electronic Component DistributorContact UsCyclops LocationContact the Team Directly
You are here: Home > Privacy Statement
Privacy statement
How we use your personal information
Cyclops Electronics Ltd is committed to protecting your personal information. This includes, but is not limited to, what you tell us about yourself; what we learn by having you as a customer, and the choices you decide regarding the types of marketing that you would like to receive.
This notice informs you about your privacy rights and how the law currently protects you under the General Data Protection Regulation (EU GDPR) and the Data Protection Act (DPA).
Our Privacy Commitment
We promise:
To keep your data safe, secure and private
Not to sell, rent or lease customer data to third parties
To provide you with ways to manage and review your marketing choices at any time
Contacting us about data privacy
If you have any queries regarding the details covered in this statement, or wish to review, edit or delete the information that we hold, then you can contact us through the contact details found at the bottom of this page.
How the law protects you
The Data Protection law states that we can only use personal information if we have a legitimate reason to do so. The lawful basis for processing personal data (as set out in Article 6 of the GDPR) are defined as being:
Consent: You will have previously given clear consent for us to process your data for a specific purpose.
Contract: The processing of personal information is necessary to undertake the fulfilment of a contract.
Legal Obligation: We must process personal information in order to comply with any current (or future) legislation.
Vital Interests: Where the processing of data would be used to protect a person’s life.
Public Tasks: When the processing of information is necessary to perform a task that would be in the public interest, or for our official functions. Any such task will need to have a clear basis in law.
Legitimate Interest: Where we would have a legitimate business or commercial interest to use your data.
The information we collect
We may collect and process the following data:
Information provided to us by completing any form on or by interacting with our website (cyclops-electronics.com). This may include, but is not limited to:
Name and company name
Contact details, such as email address and telephone number
Location information, including IP address and geographical location
Details of any previous quotations provided to you
Details of any previous orders placed by yourself
If you contact us through our website in any manner, we may keep a record of or transcript of that correspondence.
Additionally, we occasionally ask our customer’s to complete surveys that we use for research purposes and to adhere to our ISO 9001 accreditation. We will record and store that data.
Website registration information
You do not have to register to use this site, though you do need to be registered to gain access to the Members’ Area.
To become a registered user, you either need to place an order with us, or request to have an account created. In both instances, the information that we would need to create an account would be:
Your name (both forename and surname)
Your email address
Other data, such as company information, may also be required.
If you make a purchase with us, an account is automatically created with the details that we already have on record. These details will have previously been provided to us.
We keep this information secure and store it in back-ups to avoid any loss of data.
Marketing activities
We regularly send out email communications to our customers and consenting interested parties. These can include company updates and statements, promotions, industry and market news, and information that we deem as being relevant to you and the business(es) that you represent.
However, please note that we may still need to contact you via email regarding any transactional or contractual matters. For example, this could be in relation to any ongoing enquiries or any previous orders that you have placed with us.
Even if you have unsubscribed from our promotional emails, please note that we will still contact you whenever you send an enquiry to us, or make a purchase.
Automated data capture and tracking
We use email monitoring services to check emails that have been sent to our customers and consenting interested parties. By doing this, we obtain information including, but not limited to:
Whether an email has been opened or not
Responses
Which part(s) of the email that you interacted with
We also use analytical tools to collect data about visitors to our website. This can relate to information, where available, such as:
IP address
Browsing behaviour whilst on our website
Internet browser
Geographical location
This is purely statistical data about our visitors’ browsing habits and this information is used to better tailor our website to meet the needs of our users. However, we may collect and process personal information if a user begins to enter a contract with us.
Cookies
To allow our systems to recognise you and your device(s), we use cookies.
For more information about cookies and how we use them, please refer to our Cookies Policy.
Data collected and processed by external organisations
We use external organisations to monitor user behaviour and collect analytical information and other data that would be beneficial for our use. These include:
Social networks
Online advertising platforms, such as Google Adwords
Credit checking agencies and companies house
Agents, suppliers, sub-contractors and advisers
This includes types of firms that help us run our day-to-day accounts and services
This can also refer to specialist companies who advise us on ways to develop and improve our business
Market researchers
Government and law enforcement agencies
Any transfer of personal data outside of the European Union will be safeguarded under our privacy procedure process.
Retention period
As long as you have an active business relationship with us, we will indefinitely retain your information. If, at any point, that relationship ceases to exist, we will keep your data for up to 10 years.
The reasons we do this are:
To respond to a question or complaint
To study customer data as part of our own internal research
To obey any rules and legislation that apply to us about keeping records
We may also keep data for longer than 10 years if we cannot delete it for legal, regulatory or technical reasons.
Your rights
You can object to us keeping or using your information. This is known as the ‘right to object’.
You can also ask us to delete, remove or stop using your personal information if there is no need for us to keep it. This is known as the ‘right to erasure’ or the ‘right to be forgotten’.
However, please be aware that there may be legal reasons as to why we need to keep or use your data. But please inform us if you think that we should not be using it.
You can ask us to restrict the use of your personal data if:
It is not accurate
It has been used unlawfully, but you do not want us to delete it
It is not relevant any more, but you wish us to keep it for use in legal claims
You have asked us to stop using your data, but you are waiting for us to inform you whether we can keep on using it
We will not use your information while it is restricted.
If you choose not to give us your personal information
You can choose to withhold your personal information from us. However, if you decide not to give us this information, it may delay or prevent us from fulfilling our contract with you, or undertake any activity as dictated to us by law. This could mean cancelling an order that you have with us.
How to withdraw consent
You can withdraw consent at any time. Please use the unsubscribe form if you wish to do so. Alternatively, you can contact us through the contact details found at the bottom of this page.
If you do opt to withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain services to you. If this is the case, we will inform you.
How to update your personal data
If you believe the data that we hold to be incorrect, you can request for the details to be updated. This can be done either verbally or in writing. Any changes will be made within one calendar month.
How to complain
If you are unhappy with how we are using your personal information, please do contact us.
You also have the right to go to the regulator and, if you are not happy with the outcome of a complaint, lodge an appeal. The regulator is the Information Commissioner’s Office. To report a concern, or find out more information, please visit the ICO's website.
Changes to this privacy statement
We may update this privacy statement at any time, though we will always place the current version on this webpage (https://www.cyclops-electronics.com/privacystatement/)
In the event of any substantial alterations, we may contact you via email so that you are able to review any changes made.
Contact details
There are numerous ways that you can get in touch with us regarding your information.
You can:
Use this form to update your subscriptions and determine what information that we send you
Contact us directly regarding any query, complaint or request for information by completing this form or by sending an email to gdpr@cyclops-electronics.com
You can also contact us via post.
GDPR Team,Cyclops Electronics LtdCyclops HouseLink Business ParkOsbaldwick,YorkYO10 3JBUnited Kingdom
Last updated: July 2018
Component Search
Step 1
Enter Electronic Component part number below.
Step 2
Click the button below.It’s that easy.
How did you hear about our website?
Please choose...
How did you hear about our website?
Please choose...
What Our Customers SayQuality & TestingWhy Choose UsTerms and conditionsCombat CounterfeitsContact Us
Cyclops Electronics Ltd, Reg. No. SC128862, VAT No. GB561633447
Registered Office: Allan House, 25 Bothwell Street, Glasgow G2 6NL
(Registered in the United Kingdom)
© 2020 Cyclops Electronics
Website by See Green
